# **KEVIN FINN**

## Full Stack Developer

+1 (804) 460-9304 kfinn315@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/finnkevin Charlottesville, VA

#### **SUMMARY**

Well-rounded developer with ten plus years of experience building web and mobile applications focusing on .NET, JavaScript and MySQL. Highly versatile with an interest in continuous learning and mentoring others. Focused on improving lives through technology.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Full Stack Developer Charlottesville, VA

AMPEL BioSolutions LLC

05/2018 - 03/2024

- · Created, deployed, and maintained an in-house .NET Core web application to further bioinformatics research.
- Collaborated with colleagues during weekly stakeholder meetings to establish project requirements and address software issues.
- Designed and implemented responsive pages to display, search, and filter large datasets to aid research; facilitating research and publishing of more than ten academic papers by colleagues.
- Incorporated authentication and authorization using IdentityServer and the OAuth 2.0 OIDC standard, increasing app security.
- Employed Kubernetes on Google Cloud Platform to enable continuous integration and maximize deployment speed; increasing deployment speed by 70% and reducing downtime by 50%.
- · Integrated external APIs to ensure data accuracy and facilitate future capabilities.
- Designed and built a relational database for large quantities of analytic data using MySQL, allowing complex and fast queries.
- Automated the data import process using Python scripts; furthering the accuracy of the database and completeness of the data and leading to a database with over a million records.
- Constructed an API using the R language, RPlumber library and Docker to run scripts for statistical analysis, increasing the
  efficiency of scientific analysis by around fifty percent.
- · Integrated request authentication with APIs using OAuth2.0 with Bearer tokens to increase communication security.
- · Integrated unit-testing to increase app dependability; reducing bugs by 75%.
- · Implemented data entry and form validation through EntityFramework and ReactJS; expanding the application's usefulness.

# Mobile and Web App Developer

Scottsdale, AZ

Hypur Inc

2016 - 2018

- · Collaborated in an Agile team with landmark meetings including stand-ups, sprint planning, reviews and retrospectives.
- · Produced a responsive web application with .NET Core, SQL Server and JavaScript used by hundreds of customers.

# Freelance iOS and Android Developer

Multiple locations

Self-employed

2012 - 2016

· Developed mobile apps for assorted individuals and companies, focusing on education.

#### Bookseller and Merchandiser

Ramsey, NJ

Borders Books and Music

2006 - 2011

 Developed strong customer service, communication and team skills by working in a fast-paced and ever-changing environment.

### **EDUCATION**

#### BS in Computer Science

Bethlehem, PA

Lehigh University

2002 - 2006

# **SKILLS**

Agile, Android, APIs, Bash, Continuous Integration, CSS, DevOps, Docker Container, Entity Framework, Git, Github, Google Cloud, HTML, JavaScript, Kubernetes, LINQ, Linux, MySQL, OAuth 2.0, Python, R Language, ReactJS, SQL, SQL Server, Typescript